Hi, and welcome to Living in Central
Texas. If you are considering relocating
to the area, you're in the right place.
Today, we'll be exploring downtown
Belton, one of my absolute favorite
spots. With its rich history and
charming local businesses, there's just
so much to love. Plus, you're only an
hour outside of Austin, Texas, 45
minutes away from Waco, and 25 minutes
from Fort Cavazos. Let's get
[Music]
started. We are currently at Creekide
Park at Nolan Creek. This is such a cute
little spot here in Belton. Um, you have
obviously the creek behind me. And what
I like to do here a lot during the
summer especially is sit on the patio at
the gin here behind me and grab a
cocktail, grab lunch, and it's just
really peaceful outside. You can watch
the kids and families playing on the
creek. You can bring your own families,
friends down here, um, tube, hang out,
enjoy the sun. I like to come here with
my girls, grab an ice cream at the ice
cream shop, walk on over, feed the
ducks. They love it. It's just a really
great atmosphere. You also have some
really great restaurants down here. So,
aside from the gin, which is just your
Texas cuisine. You also have Corono's
deoro, which is a Mexican restaurant.
You have scores, which is like pizza and
wings. And then just around the corner,
you have Water Street Waffle Company,
which I had for breakfast. It was so
awesome. I can't wait to show you that.
That's probably my favorite breakfast
spot in all of Temple Beltton. Um, but I
think there's a lot of really great
things to see here and I can't wait to
show you. Let's go. Belton has a deep
history dating back to the 1850s when it
was founded as a key trading post. Over
the years, it's maintained that small
town charm while growing into a vibrant
community. Some other key players in our
community are definitely the medical
facilities of Baylor Scott and White as
well as the University of Mary Harden
and Baylor and newly added SpaceX in
McGregor. First up, we have Water Street
Waffle Co. And if you love a good
breakfast, this is a must visit. This is
my favorite spot in the area. Their
waffles are next level and the cozy
atmosphere makes it a great spot to
start your day. Here I have their lemon
blueberry waffle. It is so so good.
Definitely a dessert breakfast item. And
I got their drunken master skillet. Uh
it comes with syrup, but I opted out of
that. And then my friend got the three
little terminators, which he gets every
time, so they must be good.
Now, if you love shopping for unique
finds, you have to check out Cochran
Blair and Pods. I can get lost for hours
in here. It's the oldest department
store in Texas. Familyowned since
1869, you'll find everything from gifts
to home decor to boutique clothing. For
a fun night out, Beltonian is a classic,
this historic theater plays everything
from old school movies to new releases,
and they serve up some of the best
popcorn around. And you can actually
reserve this venue for special events,
which is a really nice little feature
that they offer. For amazing Thai food,
Nunas is the place to be. Their flavors
are authentic, fresh, and packed with
spice for those loving a little kick. My
top go-tos here are going to be the
chicken pad thai as well as the eggplant
tower.
The hot coffee spot in downtown Belton
is definitely Arouchia's. A great
hangout and meeting spot as well as spot
to have a little solo coffee. They have
hundreds of loose leaf teas, coffees,
pastries, and specialty tacos.
not featured in this video, but
definitely worth a mention is Blackbird
Spirits. So, this is our newest little
speak easy. It's such a cool addition to
downtown Belton. Um, if you love a good
craft cocktail or unique local spirits,
this is a hidden gem. They have an
amazing selection of small batch
spirits. and they're a bookstore, so you
can grab a cocktail, grab a book, and
have some really awesome fun right here
in Belton,
Texas. Well, that wraps up our tour of
downtown Belton, Texas. So, whether
you're looking for great food,
entertainment, or the perfect place to
call home, Belton, Texas truly has it
all. And if you are thinking about
relocating to the area, I'd love to help
you find your next dream home. And you
can find all my contact information
below. I'd love to speak with you. Don't
forget to like this video, subscribe,
and click the bell icon so that you can
stay up todate on all things real estate
here in Central Texas. Till next time.